Register of the France, Commissariat général à la famille pamphlets
Hoover Institution Archives
France, Commissariat général à la famille pamphlets
1940-1943
France. Commissariat général à la famille.
XX412
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Relates to encouragement of birth rate increase, promotion of the family as a social institution, and discouragement of alcoholism.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Agency of the Vichy government of France.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains pamphlets and booklets related to encouragement of birth rate increase, promotion of the family as a social institution, and discouragement of alcoholism.
Family--France.; France--Population.; Temperance.; World War, 1939-1945--France.
- Certificate for rural civic service, undated (Folder 1: 1)
- Flyers, 1943, undated (Folder 1: 2)
- Pamphlets and booklets (Box 1)
  - "Almanach de la famille Française", 1941-1942 (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - "La Belle Aventure de la famille", undated (Folder 1: 5)
  - "Belles Gravures en couleurs", undated (Folder 1: 6)
  - "Une Belle Mission des travailleuses sociales", undated (Folder 1: 7)
  - "Le chef et la Famille", 1942 (Folder 1: 8)
  - "Les chefs de demain seront...", 1940 (Folder 1: 9)
  - "Commerçants faites comprendre", undated (Folder 1: 10)
  - "Confederation générale des familles et des associations familiales de France", undated (Folder 1: 11)
  - "Donneriez-Vous a votre enfant ce biberon?", undated (Folder 1: 12)
  - "L'Ecole et la Famille", undated (Folder 1: 13)
  - "Ils étaient 3 petits enfants... 3 qui cherchaient une maman", undated (Folder 1: 14)
  - "Etudiant, sais tu ce qui a été fait pour toi...", undated (Folder 1: 15)
  - "Etudiant, mon camarade", undated (Folder 1: 16)
  - "Etudiants, pour vous...", undated (Folder 1: 17)
  - "Exposition de la défense de la famille Française", 1943 (Folder 1: 18)
  - "Faim", undated (Folder 1: 19)
  - "Faites confiance aux volontaires du service civique rural", undated (Folder 1: 20)
  - "La Famille dans la nation", 1943 (Folder 1: 21)
  - "La Famille Française", undated (Folder 1: 22)
  - "La France nouvelle protége la mére", undated (Folder 1: 23)
  - "Grande Exposition de la famille Française", 1943 (Folder 1: 24)
  - "L'Instituteur et son rôle dans la restauration de la famille Française", undated (Folder 1: 25)
  - Journee des meres, 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 26)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes programs and pamphlets
  - "Menaces sur l'économie Française", undated (Folder 1: 27)
  - "Paysan", undated (Folder 1: 28)
  - "Le Pharmacien et la Dénatalité", undated (Folder 1: 30)
  - "La Pharmacien et la Famille", undated (Folder 1: 31)
  - "Le Prêtre Ami et conseiller de la famille", 1942 (Folder 1: 32)
  - "Les Prisonniers et la Famille", 1943 (Folder 1: 33)
  - "Pour le Bonheur de votre foyer", undated (Folder 1: 34)
  - "Ruraux", undated (Folder 1: 35)
  - "Service civique rural", undated (Folder 1: 36)
- Postcards (Folder 1: 37)